Guide to the Arthur A. Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- October 2003 Acquisition, 1941-1987; 19.54; (18 boxes)
  - "A Guide to the Jewish Journals," Commonweal, 1966 September 30 (Box 25)
  - "Silence and Laughter According to Elie Wiesel," Jewish Heritage, 1966 (Box 25)
  - "The Retrieval of the Human," American Judaism, 1966 (Box 25)
  - "Rediscovering Judaism," Commonweal, 1966 (Box 25)
  - "Truth is Not Good Enough," American Judaism Vol. XVI No. 3, 1967 (Box 25)
  - "The Jewish Museum, Victim of Confusion," Congress bi-Weekly, 1967 (Box 25)
  - Journals, 1967 (Box 25)
  - "Confrontations with Judaism," ed. Longworth, 1966-1967 (Box 25)
  - "English Novels-American Novels," The Owl, HR & W, 1967 February 2 (Box 25)
  - "Jepthah's Vow," Jewish Chronicle, 1967 (Box 25)
  - "The Religious Situation," Beacon Press, 1967 (Box 25)
  - "Tradition and Individual Experience in Judaism," lecture at the Institute for Advanced Jewish Studies, Brandeis, 1967 November 1 (Box 25)
  - Review of "The Chocolate Dead" by Gouri, Midstream, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Review of "Those Incredible Christians" by Schonfield, New Republic, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Review of "Portrait of Yahweh as a Young God," Commonweal, 1968 December (Box 26)
  - Review of "Elder and Younger Brother" by A Roy Eckardt, Commentary, 1968 May (Box 26)
  - Review of "Exploration," Hadassah Magazine, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Essay on Marshall McLuhan, Funk & Wagnalls, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Review of "Making It" by Norman Podhoretz, Congress Bi-Weekly, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Review of "The Religious Imagination" by Rubinstein, New York Times, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Articles, 1968-1968 (Box 26)
  - Review, "Rethinking Judaism," New Republic, 1969 March (Box 26)
  - Respondsum, "Southwick on Israel," The Commonweal, 1969 January 26 (Box 26)
  - Review of "The Ambiguity of Good" by Kurt Gerstein, New York Times, 1969 April 13 (Box 26)
  - Review, "Jewish Philosophy in Modern Times," Midstream, 1969 (Box 26)
  - "Job and the Modern Imagination" review of "The Dimensions of Job; A Study and Selected Readings by N. Glatzer," Congress Bi-Weekly, 1969 May 12 (Box 26)
  - "Myth of the J-C Tradition," Commentary, 1969 November (Box 26)
  - Review, "Judaism Despite Christianity," Commentary, 1970 June (Box 26)
  - Review, Deutsch "The Non-Jew Jew," New York Times, 1969 (Box 26)
  - Articles, 1970 (Box 26)
  - Review, "In Praise of the Baal Shem Tov," Commentary, 1970 September (Box 26)
  - "The Myth of the Judeo Christian Tradition," Comentario (Argentina), 1970 January, February (Box 26)
  - Review, "Divine Disobedience" by Grey, Commonweal, 1970 (Box 26)
  - "A People Apart: Hasidism in America," essay for book with Philip Garvin, 1970 (Box 26)
  - "Hasidic Encounter," Jewish Heritage, 1971 (Box 26)
  - "Psychological Origins of F. R.'s Star of Redemption," Hugo Hahn Lecture, Midstream, 1972 February (Box 26)
  - "Museum or Mausoleum," New York Times, 1971 February 7 (Box 26)
  - Reviews, "The Pagan Rabbi" by Ozick, The Commonweal & Congress Bi-Weekly (Box 26)
  - "Three Points in Rosenweig's Star," Sh'ma, 1971 December (Box 26)
  - Review, "God's First Love Heer," Commonweal, 1971 (Box 26)
  - Review, "The New Jews," J. Sleeper & Mintz, Midstream, 1971 (Box 26)
  - "Doctrine of Contempt" review of "Jesus & Israel," Commentary, 1971 September (Box 26)
  - Review, "Brod, Paganism, Christ," Judaism, Commentary, 1971 (Box 26)
  - Letter to A. Roy Eckardt, Christianity & Crisis, 1971 November 29 (Box 26)
  - Review of "Amen" by Siegel, Commonweal, 1971 (Box 26)
  - Review of "Adam Resurrected" by Kaniuk, Congress Bi-Weekly, 1971 (Box 26)
  - Jules Isaac Review, Commentary, 1971 (Box 26)
  - "Religion & Culture," US & Canada Handbook, 1971 (Box 26)
  - Journals, 1972 (Box 26)
  - "Beyond Politics, Vision," Lecture at the 9th Annual American Jewish Congress Dialogue in Israel, Weizman Institute, Rehovot, Congress Bi-Weekly, 1971-1972 (Box 26)
  - "Willing a Messianic Marginality," Sh'ma, 1972 December 22 (Box 26)
  - Review, "Scully, Avenue of the Americas," Commonweal, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Midstream, 1973 January (Box 26)
  - Lecture at Cooper Union "The Delaunays, Apollinaire and Cendras", 1972 February 9 (Box 26)
  - "Critic's Choice," Commonweal, 1973 February 23 (Box 26)
  - Letter to the New York Times, 1973 April 13 (Box 26)
  - Review, "Firstfruits," JPS, New York Times, 1973 October (Box 26)
  - Review, "Selected Poems" by Joseph Brodsky, New York Times, 1973 December 30 (Box 26)
  - Review of an essay by Miguel de Unamuno, New York Times, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Articles, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Excerpt, "In the Days of Simon Stern Prologue," Works of Progress No. 8, Literary Guild of America, Doubleday, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Review, "The First Futurist Marinetti: Selected Writings," Commentary, 1973 May (Box 26)
  - "Nahum Glatzer as a Friend and Teacher," Jewish Heritage, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Story, excerpt from "In the Days of Simon Stern," Response, 1972-1973 (Box 26)
  - "The Last Jew on Earth," reprint in Commentary from In the Days of Simon Stern, 1973 June (Box 26)
  - "Autobiographic Notes on a Collection," "The Book Stripped Bare," Hofstra, 1973 September (Box 26)
  - "Marinetti and Futurism," Commentary, 1973 April (Box 26)
  - "On David Shapiro," Contemporary Poets of the English Language, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Introductory essay to Plotkin's "Judaism & Tragic Theology," Shocken Books, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Certificate of 1973 Edward Lewis Wallant Memorial Book Award, 1974 (Box 26)
  - "Thinking the Tremendum," Leo Baeck Memorial Lecture, 1974 (Box 26)
  - "Electra Editrice," Robert Motherwell, 1974 (Box 26)
  - Robert Motherwell Graphics, "Abstraction as Feeling," Cohen, 1974 November 21 (Box 26)
  - "Harvey Swados (1920-1972)," Simon & Schuster, unpublished, undated (Box 26)
  - "Messianism and Sabbatai Zevi," Oberlin Lecture, Midstream, 1974 (Box 26)
  - Review, "Critic's Choice," Commonweal, 1974 February 22 (Box 26)
  - "Messianism and Sabbatai Zevi," Midstream, 1974 October (Box 26)
  - "The Play of Job-1945," excerpt from In the Days of Simon Stern, Midstream, 1973 January (Box 26)
  - "Vox Clamantis in Deserto," Hadassah Magazine, 1973-1974 (Box 26)
  - "George Wittenborn," Art News, 1975 (Box 27)
  - Review of "Power Struggle" by Richard Rubenstein, Commonweal, 1975 January 3 (Box 27)
  - "Forum: What is a Jewish Book," Jewish Heritage Review, 1975 (Box 27)
  - Articles, 1974-1976 (Box 27)
  - Note for Religious Book Issue, Commonweal, 1975 January (Box 27)
  - "Mann & His Letters," Commentary, 1976 November (Box 27)
  - Interview, Arthur Cohen on Sonia Delaunay with Fay Lansner, The Feminist Art Journal, 1976-1977 (Box 27)
  - "Nothing Succeeds Like Success," New York Times, 1976 March 10 (Box 27)
  - "Futurism and Constructivism: Russian and Other," The Print Collectors Newsletter, 1976 (Box 27)
  - Review of "The Holocaust and the Literary Imagination" by Lawrence Langer, New York Times, 1975 (Box 27)
  - Articles, 1977-1978 (Box 27)
  - Review of "Abyss" by Yourcenar, New York Times, 1976 (Box 27)
  - Aggadah and Fictional Imagination, Sh'ma, 1976 January (Box 27)
  - Review of "My Search for the Messiah" by Mirsky, Commonweal, 1977 (Box 27)
  - "The Motherwell Compound," Vogue, 1977 March (Box 27)
  - Review of "On Jews & Judaism in Crisis," New York Times, 1977 (Box 27)
  - "Paradisical Origins and Disenchantment," Templegate Publishers, All Our Sons & Daughters, 1977 (Box 27)
  - "Paradisical Origins and Disenchantment," Templegate Publishers, All Our Sons & Daughters, 1977 (Box 27)
  - New York Times Guest Word, unpublished, 1977 (Box 27)
  - "Fathers: Neither Named Nor Slain," Confrontation, 1977 (Box 27)
  - Sight, Images, and Photographs, "Behold a Great Vision," Jewish Publication Society, 1978 (Box 27)
  - "Last Word," Present Tense, 1978 March (Box 27)
  - Religious Book Issue, Commonweal, 1978 March 3 (Box 27)
  - Reprint & Expanded Edition, The Natural and the Supernatural Jew, Behrman House, 1978-1979 (Box 27)
  - "Dada Spectrum: The Dialectics of Revolt," edited by Foster/Kuenzil, 1979 (Box 27)
  - Matthes & Seitz, Munich, "Junk from Outer Space", 1979 (Box 27)
  - "Decadence," review of "The Strange Life of an Epithet" by Richard Gilman, Commonweal, 1979 August 31 (Box 27)
  - "Printer-Poet's Livre D'Artiste," Kaldewey/ Print Collectors Newsletter, 1979 (Box 27)
  - "In the Matter of Mein Kampf," Op Ed, New York Times, 1979 October 4 (Box 27)
  - Letter to New York Times Book Review re: Travor-Roper on Schorske, 1980 (Box 27)
  - "Tormented Master" review of "A Life of Rabbi Nahman of Bratslav" by Arthur Green, New York Times, 1980 January 13 (Box 27)
  - "Memories of an Optimist: Sonia Delaunay 1985-1979," Art News, 1980 March (Box 27)
  - "Painting Every Surface of the World: Sonia Delaunay," American Craft, 1980 (Box 27)
  - "Liberalism and the Jews," Commentary Symposium, 1980 (Box 27)
  - "Dada Obsession," American Book Collector, 1980 (Box 27)
  - Review of "Passages in Modern Sculpture" by Rosalind Krauss, Partisan Review, 1978-1980 (Box 27)
  - "Martin Buber and Judaism," Leo Baeck Year-Book XXV, 1980 (Box 27)
  - "Our Narrative Condition," talk at Present Tense Awards Luncheon, 1980 May 6 (Box 27)
  - Acts of Theft, fee and two of Cohen's advertisements, 1980 (Box 27)
  - "American Architecture of Richard Meier," Mainliner, 1980 January (Box 27)
  - Articles, 1980 (Box 27)
  - "Rosenzweig's Method" Festschrift for Ray Hard, Scholar's Press, 1980 (Box 27)
  - Review of "World Backwards" by Compton, American Book Collector, 1981 (Box 27)
  - Lecture, "Kafka's Prague," Columbia University Series: The Writer and His City, Partisan Review, 1981 (Box 27)
  - Articles, 1980-1981 (Box 27)
  - Article on Arthur A. Cohen, "Profession: Renaissance Man" by Diane Cole, Present Tense, 1981 (Box 27)
  - Excerpt, "The Tremendum as Caesura," chapter from The Tremendum, Crosscurrent, 1980-1981 (Box 27)
  - Excerpt, "Points of Origin: Where My Mind Comes From," from An Admirable Woman, Fiction, 1981 (Box 27)
  - Lectures, Syracuse University/Williams College, 1981 (Box 27)
  - "The American Imagination: Notes on the Novel, Jews & Hope," lecture at Syracuse University, 1981 March (Box 27)
  - "Gershon Scholem," The American Scholar, 1981 (Box 27)
  - "Franz Rosenweig's The Star of Redemption," Journal of the American Academy of Religion Thematic Issue, 1981 (Box 27)
  - Articles, 1981-1983 (Box 28)
  - "Collecting Rare Books," Dollar Magazine, 1982 February (Box 28)
  - "The Religious Center of the Jews," Daedalus Beacon Press, 1982 (Box 28)
  - Rockefeller Conference Bellaggio, 1982 November (Box 28)
  - "Birth of a Zionist," Commonweal, 1982 September 12 (Box 28)
  - "Myths and Riddles: Some Observations about Literature and Theology," Bellagio Conference, 1987 (Box 28)
  - "Depero Futurists," Art News, 1982 March (Box 28)
  - Excerpt, "In Memoriam: Great Uncle Solomon," from An Admirable Woman, Moment, 1982 November (Box 28)
  - Review of "Walter Benjamin: the Story of a Friendship" by Gershom Scholem," New York Times, 1982 May 16 (Box 28)
  - "The Holocaust & Christian Theology: An Interpretation of the Problem," Israel Historical Society, 1982 June (Box 28)
  - "Russian Avant Garde Books at Sotheby's," Print Collector's Newsletter, 1982 March (Box 28)
  - Review of "Discerning the Way" by Paul Van Burent, The Journal of Religion, 1982 April (Box 28)
  - Review of "To Mend the World: Foundations of Future Jewish Thought" by Emil Fackenheim, 1982 (Box 28)
  - Review of Mircea Eliade's Autobiography, Commonweal, 1982 (Box 28)
  - "Thinking the Tremendum," German translation, Wolkensaeule and Fuerschein, Brocke & Jochum, 1982-1983 (Box 28)
  - "Endangered and Vulnerable Communities," Present Tense, 1982 (Box 28)
  - Review of "A Land of Two Peoples" by Mendes Flohr, Commonweal, 1983 October 21 (Box 28)
  - Excerpt, "Last Word from Berlin" from An Admirable Woman, Present Tense, 1983 (Box 28)
  - "The Homily of the Roses," Aggadic theme for the book Gate to the New City, a Treasury of Modern Jewish Tales, Ed Howard Schwartz, Avon, 1983 (Box 28)
  - "The Contemporaneity of Ahad Ha'am," first delivered as Yivo Lecture on April 3, 1983, Jewish Frontier, 1983 April (Box 28)
  - Review of "To Mend this World" by Fackenheim, Modern Judaism, 1982-1983 (Box 28)
  - "The Sufferings of Heinrich Von Kleist," New Criterion, 1983 (Box 28)
  - Article about AAC, "From Bauhaus to their House" by Martin Filler, House and Garden, 1983 July (Box 28)
  - Review, "Mann Diaries," New Criterion, 1983 January (Box 28)
  - Letters to Jewish Frontier addressing Israel, 1984 (Box 28)
  - Review, "Against the Apocalypse & Reflections of Nazism, New York Times, 1984 April (Box 28)
  - Letter to the New York Times regarding Lechuck's "The Death of the Jewish Novel", 1984 December (Box 28)
  - "In Our Terrible Age: The Tremendum and the Jews," Concilium, 1984 (Box 28)
  - "On Theological Method: On Behalf of the Tremendum," Journal of Reform Judaism, 1984 September (Box 28)
  - "Franz Kafka: Artist of the Incomplete," lecture, The Shattered Tablets, Orim, 1988 (Box 28)
  - Review, "Cinema Calendrier," Fine Print, 1984 July (Box 28)
  - "Erasmus," Marksih, Shimon Translation Project, 1986 (Box 28)
  - Afterward to Shimon Markish's Erasmus and the Jews, University of Chicago Press, 1986 (Box 28)
  - "Castillian Odyssey on Horseback," New York Times, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Lecture for AAR Meeting in Anaheim, "Life Amid the Paradigms or The Absence of a Jewish Critique of Culture", 1985 November (Box 28)
  - "From Eastern Europe to Paris and Beyond," The Jewish Museum catalog The Circle of Montparnasse, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Circle of Montparnasse: Jewish Artists in Paris 1900-1930, Jewish Museum, 1985 (Box 28)
  - "Embarrassed by Principle, a Present Tense Symposium," Present Tense, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Letter, "The Hidden Persuasion," Commonweal, 1985 November 1 (Box 28)
  - "Zionism and Theology," Sh'ma, 1986 December 26 (Box 28)
  - "Observations on Judaism & Modernism," talk at Awards Ceremony for the National Jewish Book award for An Admirable Woman, 1987 (Box 28)
  - "Zionism & Theology" (Leo Baseck), 1986 (Box 28)
  - "Rescue of Danish Jewry," AAC Summation lecture, 1987 (Box 28)
  - Contemporary Jewish Religious Thought, undated (Box 28)
  - Cohen, contributions to Contemporary Jewish Religious Thought, undated (Box 28)
  - Lecture, "Franz Kafka: Artist of the Incomplete," YMHA, Orim, 1988 (Box 28)
  - "On the Marionette Theater," Edition Gunnar Kaldewey, 1988 (Box 28)
  - "Redemption, Theology, Resurrection of the Dead," editor's introduction to Contemporary Jewish Religious Thought, 1987 (Box 28)
  - Kleist Book, 1985-1988 (Box 28)
  - Herbert Bayer, reviews and award, 1985-1986 (Box 28)
  - Conjunctions, 1992 (Box 28)
  - Articles, 1984-1987 (Box 28)
  - Personal correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1958 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1959 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: editorial & magazine, 1957-1959 (Box 29)
  - Open End (television), 1959 (Box 29)
  - Comments on articles, 1955-1957 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: editorial, magazine, and speaking engagements, 1960 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: theological or of theological interest, 1957 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: theological, 1960 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: filed & unanswered, 1960-1961 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: editorial, 1961 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: theological, 1958-1959 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: theological, 1961 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: lectures, 1961 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: theological, 1962 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: lectures, etc., 1962 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: editorial, 1962 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: theological, 1963 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: Jewish-Christian, 1962-1964 (Box 29)
  - Lectures and appearances, 1963 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: declinations of invitations, 1963 (Box 29)
  - Peace Now Movement, 1982, undated (Box 29)
  - Speaking & writing, 1964 (Box 29)
  - Speaking & writing, 1965 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: lectures, 1965 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: writing & speaking, 1966 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: speaking engagements, 1974 (Box 29)
  - Speaking engagements, Spring, 1974 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: speaking, 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: speaking, writing, lectures, 1968 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: lectures & writing, 1967 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1969 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1970 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1971 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1973 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1974 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 29)
  - Lecture, 1975 (Box 30)
  - New Jewish Agenda, 1983 (Box 30)
  - Forth Coming, 1983 (Box 30)
  - Modern Jewish Thought, Steven Katz, modern Jewish Masters Series, 1982 (Box 30)
  - Yerushalmi University, seminars on Israel & Jewish Studies, 1981 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1985-1986 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1985 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1984 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1983 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1982 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1981 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1980 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1978 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1977 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: professional, 1975 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Permissions: correspondence, 1959-1981 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: Israeli writers, 1984-1985, undated (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: general & personal, 1985 (Box 31)
  - Israel, 1985 (Box 31)
  - Authors Guild card, 1986 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1986 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal & professional, 1982 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1982 (Box 31)
  - Metz, Johann Baptist correspondence, 1983 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1983 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1980 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1984 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1979 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1978 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1981 (Box 31)
  - Van Buren, Paul, 1981 (Box 31)
  - Graf, Otto, 1976 (Box 31)
  - Sartorius, Joachim & Christa, 1979-1984, undated (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1977 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1975 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1976 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1973 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1972 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1974 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1969 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1970 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1971 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1960 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1962 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1963 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1964 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1965 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1967 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1968 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1965 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence: personal, 1961 (Box 31)
  - Shon, Greta, 1966-1968 (Box 31)
  - Gendler, Everett: correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 31)
  - Audiocassettes (Box 32)
  - Introduction (unidentified), undated (Box 32)
  - A Youth Looks at His World, bound manuscript, undated (Box 32)
  - Poems, unpublished, 1963-1964, undated (Box 32)
  - Cohen, Play/Saul, undated (Box 32)
  - A Hero in His Time, Juki Kasher translation, undated (Box 32)
  - The Trial of Jeremiah, play, 1958, undated (Box 32)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 32)
  - Novel: Levi, 1984, undated (Box 32)
  - Marginality, undated (Box 32)
  - The Adam Man, play, 1967-1968 (Box 32)
  - The Last Soliloquy and Other One Act Plays, 1968 (Box 32)
  - Institute for Advanced Judaic Studies, 1963-1964 (Box 33)
  - Leo Baeck, 1983-1984 (Box 33)
  - Yivo Library of Yiddish (Jewish) Classics, 1984-1985 (Box 33)
  - Pen American Center, 1983-1985, undated (Box 33)
  - American-Israeli Civil Rights Coalition, Kol Koreh, 1982 (Box 33)
  - Commentary Magazine, 1961-1970 (Box 33)
  - Commonweal, 1978 (Box 33)
  - Cross Currents, undated (Box 33)
  - Franz Rosenzweig Society, 1958-1961 (Box 33)
  - Guggenheim Application, 1979 (Box 33)
  - Guggenheim Application, 1982-1983 (Box 33)
  - Historia Judaica, 1962 (Box 33)
  - World & Meridian, 1961-1962, undated (Box 33)
  - Seldes: Russell & Volkening, 1975-1979, undated (Box 33)
  - Yivo Current Business Farvaltung, 1984, undated (Box 33)
  - Yivo correspondence, 1983 (Box 33)
  - Yivo general correspondence, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Yivo, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Synagogues of Poland Project, 1985, undated (Box 33)
  - Vatican Council II on Jews and related, 1965, undated (Box 33)
  - Cohen, Gershom, Jewish Theology Seminary, 1981-1985, undated (Box 33)
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1967-1978, undated (Box 33)
  - Holt, Rinehart & Winston, 1962-1968, undated (Box 33)
  - Orim Jewish Journal at Yale, 1985 (Box 33)
  - The Jewish Museum, 1962-1971 (Box 33)
  - Fund for the Republic: Hutchins, 1956-1964 (Box 33)
  - KPFA FM Berkeley, 1958 (Box 33)
  - Ramparts Editorial Board, 1965-1972 (Box 33)
  - The History of the Idea of Friendship, 1964 (Box 33)
  - Judaism, a Quarterly Review, 1961-1970 (Box 33)
  - WBAI FM Broadcasting, 1962-1964 (Box 33)
  - Vietnam Protest Activities, 1967-1968 (Box 33)
  - Meridian Books, 1962 (Box 33)
  - PEN American Center, 1966 (Box 33)
  - New York Committee to Abolish Capital Punishment, 1962-1963 (Box 33)
  - The Four C's Conferences, 1962-1963 (Box 33)
  - Pacem in Terris Convocation, 1965 (Box 33)
  - PEN Literary Auction, 1978 May (Box 33)
  - Midstream, correspondence (Box 33)
  - Acts of Theft, reviews, 1980 (Box 34)
  - Acts of Theft, reviews, Secker & Warb. England, 1980 April (Box 34)
  - Acts of Theft, publicity correspondence, 1980 (Box 34)
  - An Admirable Woman, reviews, 1983-1984 (Box 34)
  - An Admirable Woman, Carcanet Lit., English Edition, 1984-1985 (Box 34)
  - An Admirable Woman, publicity, 1983-1984 (Box 34)
  - An Admirable Woman, reader's comments, 1983-1984 (Box 34)
  - An Admirable Woman, outline, undated (Box 34)
  - An Admirable Woman, Washington Jewish Book Fair, 1983 November 6 (Box 34)
  - An Admirable Woman, advertising, 1983 (Box 34)
  - An Admirable Woman, publishing correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 34)
  - An Admirable Woman, David Godine correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 34)
  - Acts of Theft, publicity department correspondence, Harcourt, Brace, Jovanovich, 1979 (Box 34)
  - Acts of Theft, English Edition, Secker & Warburg, 1980 March (Box 34)
  - Acts of Theft, publisher correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 34)
  - Acts of Theft, reader correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 34)
  - Arguments & Doctrines, Harper & JPS, reviews and publicity, 1970-1971 (Box 34)
  - Arguments & Doctrines, Harper & JPS, publisher correspondence, 1964-1970 (Box 34)
  - Arguments and Doctrines, JPS, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Der Jude: Essays from Buber's Journal, publicity and press comment, 1981 (Box 34)